Guide to the Arthur Davison Ficke Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1897-1968; Series IV; 3; (7 boxes)
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison
    - Scrapbook: "Essays on the Art of Asia", [1916-40?] (Box 49, Folder 1504)
    - Scrapbook: "Fables of Angels and Animals", 1938-39 (Box 50, Folder 1505)
    - Supreme Court of Iowa certificate of admission, 1908 Jun 5
    - Tributes, 1945-53 (Box 50, Folder 1506)
    - Will, 1944-45 (Box 50, Folder 1507)
  - Ficke, Betty: memorial service, 1903 Mar 25 (Box 50, Folder 1508)
  - Ficke, Charles August, 1917 (Box 50, Folder 1509)
  - Ficke, Evelyn Blunt: clippings, 1921, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1510)
  - Ficke, Evelyn Blunt: diary, 1917, 1920 (Box 50, Folder 1511)
  - Ficke, Frances Davison: will, 1942 (Box 51, Folder 1512)
  - Ficke, Gladys Brown
    - Clippings, 1941-62, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1513-1522)
    - Diaries, 1917, 1924 (Box 51, Folder 1523-1524)
    - Greek tour, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 1525-1526)
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-68, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1527)
    - Notes, 1938-51 (Box 51, Folder 1528-1532)
    - Will, 1940-45 (Box 51, Folder 1533)
  - Ficke family: genealogical information, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1534)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1911-1949; Series V; 1; (3 boxes)
  Series V, Business and Legal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Balance sheets, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 1535)
  - Checkbook statements, 1944-45 (Box 52, Folder 1536-1539)
  - Correspondence, 1917-47 (Box 52, Folder 1540-1557)
  - Ficke, Charles August: estate
    - Balance sheets, 1942-43 (Box 52, Folder 1558-1561)
    - Correspondence, 1923-45 (Box 52, Folder 1562-1568)
    - Miscellaneous, 1911-31 (Box 53, Folder 1569)
  - Income tax, 1917-37 (Box 53, Folder 1570-1583)
  - Income tax suit
    - Correspondence, 1941-53 (Box 53, Folder 1584-1596)
    - Income tax returns, 1940-43 (Box 53, Folder 1597-1600)
    - Investment statements, 1936-48 (Box 53, Folder 1601-1604)
    - Ledgers, 1940-48 (Box 53, Folder 1605)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943-49 (Box 53, Folder 1606)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1607)
    - Receipts, 1945-48 (Box 54, Folder 1608)
  - Investment statements, 1931-46 (Box 54, Folder 1609-1611)
  - Medical
    - Army disability: correspondence, 1926-47 (Box 54, Folder 1612-1618)
    - Army disability: notes, 1931-36, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1619)
    - Expenses, 1945-46 (Box 54, Folder 1620)
  - Miscellaneous, 1931-33, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1621)
  - Worksheets, 1921-40 (Box 54, Folder 1622-1624)
- Arthur Davison Ficke Foundation, 1946-1970; Series VI; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Series VI, Arthur Davison Ficke Foundation, is arranged by alphabetically by subject.
  - Bills and receipts, 1949-51 (Box 55, Folder 1625)
  - Chart: "Primary Process," holograph, n.d.
  - Clippings, z1950 (Box 55, Folder 1626)
  - Correspondence, 1946-63 (Box 55, Folder 1627-1642)
  - Conference on the Scientific Investigation of the Creative Process: typescript, mimeograph (6 copies), 1949 Dec 9 (Box 55, Folder 1643)
  - Memorial meeting: address, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1644)
  - Minutebook and organizational records, 1949-50 (Box 55, Folder 1645)
  - Minutes, 1950 Jun 22 (Box 55, Folder 1646)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1964, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1647)
  - Notebooks, 1950-60 (Box 55, Folder 1648-1651)
  - Notebooks, 1960, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1652-1656)
  - Notes: holograph, typescript, and printed material (Box 56, Folder 1657-1661)
  - Notes: City and Country School, holograph and typescript, 1951-52 (Box 56, Folder 1662)
  - Notes: "Lucy," holograph and typescript, 1951-53 (Box 56, Folder 1663)
  - Notes: Rapaport, David, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1664)
  - Notes: rhythm, holograph, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1665)
  - Notes: "Sally," holograph and typescript, 1957-59 (Box 56, Folder 1666-1670)
  - Notes: "Sally": holograph and typescript, mimeograph, 1959-60 (Box 57, Folder 1671-1681)
  - Notes: "Stevie," holograph and typescript, 1952-53 (Box 57, Folder 1682)
  - Notes: Seminars, typescript, [1951]-52 (Box 57, Folder 1683)
  - Notes: sublimation, 1951, 1956 (Box 58, Folder 1684-1685)
  - Notes: theory, holograph, 1950-51, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1686)
  - Organization, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 1687)
  - Round table discussion, 1949 Dec 9 (Box 58, Folder 1688)
  - 21st International Congress of Psychoanalysis, 1959 Jul 26-30 (Box 58, Folder 1689)
  - Writings: Ficke, Gladys Brown
    - "An Artist Looks at Psychoanalysis": typescript, original (2 copies), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1690)
      See also: Series II, Box 37, folder 1170
    - "An Artist Ruminates About Psychoanalytic Studies of Creative Process": notes, holograph, typescript, and printed, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 1691)
    - "An Artist Ruminates About Psychoanalytic Studies of Creative Process": typescript, original; and typescript, carbon (3 copies), [ca. 1964] (Box 58, Folder 1692)
    - "An Artist Ruminates About Pschoanalytic Studies of Creative Process": correspondence, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 1693)
    - "A Technique for the Study of the Process of Painting in Children": typescript, original, corrected, three drafts, [1964] (Box 58, Folder 1694)
    - "A Technique for the Study of the Process of Painting in Children": typescript carbon, corrected, three drafts, [1964] (Box 58, Folder 1695)
    - "A Technique for the Study of the Process of Painting in Children": illustrations, 1964 Apr 7 (Box 58, Folder 1696)
    - "A Technique for the Study of the Process of Painting in Children": galley proof, corrected, 1964 Apr 9, 16 (Box 58, Folder 1697)
    - "A Technique for the Study of the Process of Painting in Children": printed version, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 1698)
    - "A Technique for the Study of the Process of Painting in Children": correspondence, 1963-64 (Box 58, Folder 1699-1700)
  - Writings: Frois-Whittmann, Jean (Gladys Brown, trans.)
    - "Psychoanalytic Considerations of Modern Art": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1701)
  - Writings: Gross, Dr. Albert
    - "Malignancy": holograph, [ca. 1949-50] (Box 58, Folder 1702)
      With notes by Gladys Brown Ficke, holograph and typescript.
  - Writings: Kubie, Lawrence S.
    - "The Neurotic Potential and Human Adaptation": typescript, mimeograph, 1949 Mar 31 (Box 58, Folder 1703)
  - Writings: Rosen, Victor H.
    - "The Relevance of "Style" to Certain Aspects of Defense", and "The Synthetic Function of the Ego": meeting of the "Gifted Adolescent Project", 1960 Jun 20 (Box 58, Folder 1704)
    - "Some Effects of Artistic Talent on Character Style": typescript, mimeograph, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1705)
      With notes by Gladys Brown Ficke, and correspondence between Gladys Brown Ficke and Victor H. Rosen.
  - Writings: Rothenberg, Dr. Albert
    - "Autobiographical Drama: Strindberg and O'Neill": typescript, photostat (Box 58, Folder 1706)
    - "Poetic Process and Psychotherapy": typescript, photocopy (Box 58, Folder 1707)
    - "Psychedelism: Dionysis Reborn": typescript, carbon and photostat (Box 58, Folder 1708)
  - Writings: Werkman, Sidney L.
    - "The Eye of Childhood (Pyschiatric Myths and Media Realities)": reprint, 1970 Sep 7 (Box 58, Folder 1709)
- Artwork, 1906-1942; Series VII; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series VII, Artwork, is arranged alphabetically by artist.
  - Aldis, Mary. "Ghostly Caperings," watercolor, inscribed and signed
  - Atl, Dr. Gerardo Murillo. "El Cerro De Xaltopec," drawing, annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke, 1935
  - Bauman, Gustave. "Bright Angel Trail," [silkscreen?], n.d.
  - Du Bois, Guy Pène. [Dancers], pencil and ink drawing, inscribed by the artist to Gladys Ficke (Box 59, Folder 1710)
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison (Box 59, Folder 1711)
    - "Ancient Chinese Jade", 1942
    - "Ancient Chinese Phoenix-Stone", 1942
    - "Chinese Phoenix-Stone Cut and Uncut", [1942]
    - "Christmas, 1942"
    - Untitled, [1942]
    - "Fate of the Earth", [1942]
    - "Grow Not Too High, Grow Not Too Far From Home", [1942]
      All are watercolor and ink on paper.
    - "The Assignation," watercolor and ink
    - "The Beloved," watercolor and ink
    - "Cytherea," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Diagram of a Certain Chemical Reaction," watercolor and ink
    - "Dragon in Very Early Youth," watercolor and ink
    - "The Earth-Scorner," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Evil," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "The Friend of Man," watercolor and ink
    - "The Ghost That Loved the Moon," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Graphic Representation of the Fourth Dimension," watercolor and ink
    - "The Heaven-Hater," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Invitation to the Dance," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "The Liberation of the Poet," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "The Maiden," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Mooncalf," watercolor and ink
    - "Noon," watercolor and ink
    - [Nude woman], watercolor and ink
      Labeled on back: "Aki of the Sanyodo."
    - "Observation by the Astronomer of Cork Hill," watercolor and ink
    - "Organic Study in Circular Rythms," watercolor and ink
    - "Patagonia," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "The Pomegranate," watercolor and ink
    - "Portrait of Edna St. Vincent Millay," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
      Also titled "Portrait of a Poetess."
    - "Portrait of a Poet," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Resignation," water and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Ruins of Hoboken," watercolor and ink
    - "Ruins of Karnak," watercolor and ink
    - "Self-Portrait," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "The Soul Looks Within Seeking to Discover its True Color," watercolor and ink
    - "Spectra," watercolor and ink
    - "Study in Heraldry and Color," watercolor and ink
    - "Study in Japanese Imperial Heraldry," watercolor and ink
    - "Study in Profane Emotion," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Study in Religious Emotion," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph
    - "Symphonic Study in Three Circular Rythms," ink and watercolor
    - "Three Travellers Toward Japan in February 1917," watercolor and ink (Box 59, Folder 1712)
    - "The Wrong Madonna," watercolor and ink
    - Untitled, watercolor and ink
      Labeled on back: "Yuchizen of the Hokurikudo."
    - Untitled, watercolor and ink
      Labeled on back: "Moriyama Kiso Kaido."
  - Ficke, Gladys Brown. Six pencil and ink drawings (Box 59, Folder 1713)
  - Ganso, Emil. [Café Scene], pen and ink
  - Harrison, Carol. [Trees], oil, signed, n.d.
  - Lowell, Orson
    - [At the matinee], oil, n.d.
    - [In the manager's office], oil, n.d.
  - Lundgren, Eric
    - [Christmas card], crayon drawing, signed, 1937 (Box 59, Folder 1714)
    - [Couple dancing], etching, n.d.
    - [Dog at a garbage can], lithograph, n.d.
    - [Street scene], etching, n.d.
    - "Vine Street Provincetown," etching, n.d.
    - "Mrs. Morton Buys a Fish," lithograph, n.d.
      Annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke, 1938.
  - Miller, Kenneth Hayes. [Female Nude], etching, n.d.
  - Nash, Willard. [Merry-go-round], etching
    Inscribed to Gladys and Arthur Ficke, 1927 Dec.
  - O'Neill, Rose. [Figure], reproduction of a chalk drawing, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1715)
    Inscribed to Arthur Ficke.
  - Perdriat, Hélène
    - "Self Portrait," etching, n.d.
    - [Three nude women], etching, n.d.
  - Roberts, Virginia Allen. [Nude woman], [lithograph?], signed, n.d.
  - Shuster, Will. "Sanctuario-Chimayo," etching, inscribed, 1928 (Box 59, Folder 1716)
  - Sloan, John
    - [The artist, his wife and friends], etching, 1906
    - "Dolly and John 25th Wedding Anniversary Aug 5/26," etching, signed, 1926 (Box 59, Folder 1717)
    - "Girl Seated," drypoint, signed, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1718)
    - "Prone Nude," etching, signed, 1913 (Box 59, Folder 1719)
  - Stamos, Theodoros. [Hardhack, Hillsdale, N. Y.], oil painting, n.d. (Box art, Folder 1720)
- Oversize, 11; (7 boxes)
  - Mr. Faust
    - Third plan: holograph, final draft (in Series II), [ca. 1912] (Box 60, Folder 1721)
    - Publicity (in Series II), 1921 (Box 60, Folder 1722)
  - Tumultuous Shore
    - Later page proof, corrected (in Series II), 1942 Feb (Box 60, Folder 1722a)
    - Contract (in Series II) (Box 60, Folder 1723)
  - [Empty folder] (Box 60, Folder 1724)
  - Adams, Ansel
    - "Aspen": inscribed to Arthur Davison Ficke (in Series III), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1725)
    - "Monolith": signed (in Series III), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1726)
    - "Robinson Jeffers": inscribed by Jeffers to Arthur Davison Ficke, 1928 Feb (Box 60, Folder 1727)
    - "Snow": signed (in Series III), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1728)
  - Aldis, Arthur: portrait by Hugh McKean (in Series III), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1729)
  - Aldis, Mary Reynolds (2 portraits) (in Series III), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1730)
  - Carman, Bliss: 2 photographs by Arthur Davison Ficke (in Series III), 1927 (Box 60, Folder 1731)
  - Devoe, Alan: signed (in Series III), 1939 Sep 17 (Box 60, Folder 1732)
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison
    - 2 portraits in military uniform (in Series III), 1919 (Box 61, Folder 1733)
    - Portrait (2 copies) (in Series III), [ca. 1921] (Box 61, Folder 1734)
    - Photograph by Witter Bynner in Santa Fe, annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke (in Series III), 1927 (Box 61, Folder 1735)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Witter Bynner, and Bliss Carman, Santa Fe (in Series III), 1927 (Box 61, Folder 1736)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Edna St. Vincent Millay, and Gladys Brown Ficke in Santa Fe (in Series III), [ca. 1927] (Box 61, Folder 1737-1738)
    - Photograph by Witter Bynner (in Series III), 1928 (Box 61, Folder 1739)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and John Cowper Powys, Santa Fe (in Series III), [ca. 1928] (Box 61, Folder 1740)
    - Photograph by Martin Hagget (in Series III), 1934 (Box 61, Folder 1741)
    - Portrait by Rose O'Neill (in Series III), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1742)
    - Four photographs of paintings by Bror Julius Olsson Norfeldt (in Series III), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1743)
  - Ficke, Charles August
    - Portrait By F. A. Free, Davenport, Iowa (in Series III), 1926 (Box 61, Folder 1744)
    - Portrait by Hostetler, Davenport, Iowa (in Series III), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1745)
  - Ficke, Gladys Brown
    - Portrait (in Series III), 1921 (Box 61, Folder 1746)
    - Four photographs in Santa Fe (in Series III), [1927] (Box 61, Folder 1747)
  - Genthe, Arnold
    - [Female nude seated] (in Series III), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1748)
    - [Female nude standing] (in Series III)
    - [Woman's hand holding jade] (in Series III)
  - Jeffers, Robinson: 4 photographs by Arthur Davison Ficke (in Series III), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1749)
  - Kroll, Leon. Photograph by William McKillop of untitled painting, inscribed by Kroll to Gladys Brown (in Series III), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1749a)
  - Lundgren, Eric (in Series III) (Box 61, Folder 1750)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, Santa Fe (in Series III), [ca. 1927] (Box 61, Folder 1751)
  - Phillpotts, Eden, inscribed to Arthur Davison Ficke (in Series III), 1931 Jun (Box 61, Folder 1752)
  - [Santa Fe] (in Series III), [ca. 1927] (Box 61, Folder 1753)
  - Taos church, photographed by Carl Van Vechten (in Series III), 1933 Jul 15 (Box 61, Folder 1754)
  - Harvard University diploma (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1755)
  - Supreme Court of Iowa certificate of admission (in Series IV), 1908 Jun 5 (Box 61, Folder 1756)
  - Military papers
    - Appointment as Captain in the United States Army (in Series IV), 1917 Oct 12 (Box 61, Folder 1757)
    - Appointment as Major in the United States Army (in Series IV), 1918 Jan 22 (Box 61, Folder 1758)
    - Citation, United States Army (in Series IV), 1919 May 7 (Box 61, Folder 1759)
  - Investment statements (in Series V), 1931-33 (Box 61, Folder 1760)
  - Chart: "Primary Process," holograph (in Series VI), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1761)
  - "Ballad!!! Ballad!!! Ballad!!!," poem, typescript carbon, annotated (in Series II) (Box 62, Folder 1762)
  - "Nannie and Warren - An American Ballad," typescript (in Series II), 1928 Jan 1 (Box 62, Folder 1763)
  - Citation. République Française. Croix de Chevalier du Mérite agricole (in Series IV), 1919 Sep 24 (Box 62, Folder 1764)
  - Aldis, Mary. "Ghostly Caperings," watercolor, inscribed and signed (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1765)
  - Atl, Dr. Gerardo Murillo. "El Cerro De Xaltopec," drawing, annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke (in Series VII), 1935 (Box 63, Folder 1766)
  - Bauman, Gustave. "Bright Angel Trail," [silkscreen?] (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1767)
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison
    - "The Assignation," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1768)
    - "The Beloved," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1769)
    - "Cytherea," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1770)
    - "Diagram of a Certain Chemical Reaction," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1771)
    - "Dragon in Very Early Youth," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1772)
    - "The Earth-Scorner," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1773)
    - "Evil," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1774)
    - "The Friend of Man," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1775)
    - "The Ghost That Loved the Moon," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1776)
    - "Graphic Representation of the Fourth Dimension," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1777)
    - "The Heaven-Hater," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1778)
    - "Invitation to the Dance," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1779)
    - "The Liberation of the Poet," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1780)
    - "The Maiden," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1781)
    - "Mooncalf," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1782)
    - "Noon," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1783)
    - [Nude woman], watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1784)
    - "Observation by the Astronomer of Cork Hill," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1785)
    - "Organic Study in Circular Rythms," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1786)
    - "Patagonia," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1787)
    - "The Pomegranate," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1788)
    - "Portrait of Edna St. Vincent Millay," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1789)
    - "Portrait of a Poet," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1790)
    - "Resignation," water and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1791)
    - "Ruins of Hoboken," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1792)
    - "Ruins of Karnak," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1793)
    - "Self-Portrait," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1794)
    - "The Soul Looks Within Seeking to Discover its True Color," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1795)
    - "Spectra," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1796)
    - "Study in Heraldry and Color," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1797)
    - "Study in Japanese Imperial Heraldry," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1798)
    - "Study in Profane Emotion," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1799)
    - "Study in Religious Emotion," watercolor and ink, with poem, holograph (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1800)
    - "Symphonic Study in Three Circular Rythms," ink and watercolor (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1801)
    - "The Wrong Madonna," watercolor and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1802)
    - Untitled, watercolor and ink labeled on back: "Yuchizen of the Hokurikudo" (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1803)
    - Untitled, watercolor and ink labeled on back: "Moriyama Kiso Kaido" (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1804)
  - Ganso, Emil. [Café Scene], pen and ink (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1805)
  - Harrison, Carol. [Trees], oil, signed (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1806)
  - Lundgren, Eric
    - [Couple dancing], etching (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1807)
    - [Dog at a garbage can], lithograph (in Series VII), n.d.
    - [Street scene], etching (in Series VII), n.d.
    - "Vine Street Provincetown," etching (in Series VII), n.d.
    - "Mrs. Morton Buys a Fish," lithograph (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1808)
  - Miller, Kenneth Hayes. [Female Nude], etching (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1809)
  - Nash, Willard. [Merry-go-round], etching (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1810)
  - Perdriat, Hélène
    - "Self Portrait," etching (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1811)
    - [Three nude women], etching (in Series VII), n.d.
  - Roberts, Virginia Allen. [Nude woman], [lithograph?], signed (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1812)
  - Sloan, John. [The artist, his wife and friends], etching (in Series VII), 1906 (Box 63, Folder 1813)
  - China: photograph album (in Series III), 1920 (Box 64, Folder 1814)
  - Japan: photograph album (in Series III), 1917 (Box 65, Folder 1815)
  - Tumultuous Shore
    - Early page proof, corrected (in Series II), 1942 Jan (Box 66, Folder 1816)
    - Intermediate page proof, corrected (in Series II), 1942 Jan (Box 66, Folder 1817)
    - Later page proof, corrected (in Series II), 1942 Feb (Box 66, Folder 1818)
  - Lowell, Orson
    - [At the matinee], oil (in Series VII), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 1819)
    - [In the manager's office], oil (in Series VII), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 1820)
  - [Empty folder] (Box bsd, folder 1821)
- Restricted, 1; (3 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 67-69 contain materials restricted until 2023 Dec 31. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
  - Gladys Brown Ficke Personal Papers (Box 67, Folder 1822)
  - Gladys Brown Ficke Personal Papers (Box 68, Folder 1823)
  - Gladys Brown Ficke Personal Papers (Box 69, Folder 1824)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.42; (1 box)
  Restricted Fragile Papers contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints have been substituted in the main files for reference use.
  Box 70 and Folder 1387a (Cold storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 45, folder 1426a; Box 45, folder 1434a; Box 47, folder 1476 (Box 70, Folder 1825)